<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | Xiang (Shawn) Fei</title>
    <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication-type/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://EdgarFx.github.io/media/icon_hu511fa36bc4ff2d03adc724be90fee2b8_24177_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication-type/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAC-VI-Init: Robust Visual-Inertial Initialization and Calibration with Learning-based Features and Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication/mac_vi_init/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication/mac_vi_init/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents MAC-VI-Init, a robust and accurate method for VI initialization and online calibration. Traditional approaches often struggle in challenging environments - such as severe illumination changes, dynamic objects, occlusions, and fast motions - due to their reliance on geometric visual features. Our method leverages learning-based feature matching and metrics-aware covariance to robustly estimate visual poses. Moreover, we explicitly compute the covariance of these visual poses to enable more effective joint VI optimization. A learning-based IMU model, AirIMU, can further be incorporated to provide precise IMU corrections and reliable uncertainty estimates for IMU pre-integration. Experiments in challenging scenarios demonstrate that our approach substantially improves the robustness and accuracy compared with existing methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin: 2rem 0;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Successful Initialization Comparison on V102 Sequence of EuRoC dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;NC Demo&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; border-radius: 8px; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px rgba(0,0,0,0.1);&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Disclosure Effect, Corporate Fundamentals, and Net-zero Emission Target: Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication/disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/publication/disclosure/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
