<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carbon Market | Xiang (Shawn) Fei</title>
    <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/tag/carbon-market/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://EdgarFx.github.io/tag/carbon-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Carbon Market</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://EdgarFx.github.io/media/icon_hu511fa36bc4ff2d03adc724be90fee2b8_24177_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Carbon Market</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/tag/carbon-market/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear-Layer-Enhanced Quantum Long Short-Term Memory for Carbon Price Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/l_qlstm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/l_qlstm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accurate carbon price forecasting is important for investors and policymakers to make decisions in the carbon market. With the development of quantum computing in recent years, quantum machine learning has shown great potential in a wide range of areas. The aim of this research theme is to try to adapt Quantum Long Short-Term Memory to forecast the carbon price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Disclosure Effect, Corporate Fundamentals, and Net-zero Emission Target: Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/disclosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the national net-zero emission target, carbon disclosure becomes more significant for investors to evaluate corporate climate risk in formulating investing strategies. This study aims to analyze the impact of Carbon Disclosure on Company Financial Performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Disclosure Effect, Corporate Fundamentals, and Net-zero Emission Target: Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/ets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/ets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper conducts an empirical analysis of the impact of China’s national and regional Emissions Trading Scheme (ETS) on the ﬁnancial performance of listed companies. A comprehensive dataset is constructed, encompassing ﬁrm-level carbon allowance data and ﬁrm-level emission data from July 2021 to December 2022. Our ﬁndings indicate that, in the initial years of China’s ETS implementation, companies participating in the national ETS experienced a statistically signiﬁcant superior performance compared to non-participating ﬁrms due to excess free carbon emission allowances. Results also show that National ETS resulted in a statistically signiﬁcant reduction in emissions of regulated companies. Nevertheless, involvement in the regional ETS yielded no discernible e↵ect on the ﬁnancial and environmental performance of regulated entities. The outcomes reveal the existence of a substantial and statistically signiﬁcant ”over-allocation of carbon allowances,” predominantly attributable to increased non-operational income of regulated companies in China’s national ETS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Carbon Rating Report of China&#39;s 100 Overseas Listed Companies</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/carbon_rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/carbon_rating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At present, there is no unified definition of the organizational boundary, scope and management for corporate carbon emission information disclosure in China. China-based Stock Exchanges have no mandatory disclosure requirements for carbon emission information of listed companies either. In the absence of uniform standards, there may be inconsistencies in the statistical methodologies of corporate carbon information disclosure, resulting in the lack of comparability among different emission data. Domestic regulatory authorities need to establish a unified corporate carbon information disclosure standard to supervise the carbon information disclosure of listed companies and assist companies, thus to carry out standardized disclosure. Carbon disclosure is now of great practical significance to the development of enterprises. The leading enterprises in the capital market generally have higher disclosure levels, which will be in turn incentivized by the stock market, thus forming a positive cycle. At the same time, with the national carbon peaking and carbon neutrality policy in place, carbon disclosure, as a social and environmental factor, will continuously be the focus of the capital market. It will also have a greater impact on a company’s stock price, profits and other financial performances. Therefore, it is even more imperative for all companies to improve their own carbon emission management and disclosure systems. While achieving emission reduction targets, they should also reduce the carbon emission intensity and improve the quality of carbon information disclosure. This report proposes a carbon rating system and releases the carbon rating of China’s 100 Overseas Listed Companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
