<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power System | Xiang Fei</title>
    <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/tag/power-system/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://EdgarFx.github.io/tag/power-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Power System</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://EdgarFx.github.io/media/icon_hu511fa36bc4ff2d03adc724be90fee2b8_24177_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Power System</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/tag/power-system/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Based Power System Fault Diagnosis with QAOA and Efficient Gate Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/q_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/q_optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Power system fault diagnosis helps to reproduce the fault process and provide the dispatchers with a basis for fault decision-making. The aim of this research theme is to try to adapt quantum approximate optimization algorithm to solve power system fault diagnosis problem under current hardware limit, utilizing the potential advantages of quantum computing to handle more complex power system faults.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation Modeling Analysis of Carbon-Electricity Market in the Context of Carbon Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EdgarFx.github.io/research/simulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper studied carbon market clearing, electricity market clearing, and computable general equilibrium (CGE) models to simulate carbon, electricity, and macro-economy systems. A hybrid experimental learning method is applied to simulate the carbon-electricity market, which solves the macro-scale problems from the conflict between electricity market price reduction and carbon emission cost, and the micro-scale problems from the different decision time scales. Based on the simulation framework, we can study the electricity market forecasting analysis techniques. Based on the Guangdong trial spot market, a case study on a 3-bus electricity market is launched to test the proposed method&amp;rsquo;s adaption in the bidding behavior modeling of the electricity market. Moreover, a CGE experiment finds out that the carbon market can reduce the emission amount of the eight industries. And the carbon price can affect each industry&amp;rsquo;s emission amount, however, it has little effect on the total amount. This work is supported by The Science and Technology Project of State Grid Zhejiang Electric Power Co., Ltd. “Research on Carbon Trading System Based on Blockchain Technology” (Grant NO.5211LS21N002).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
